{
  "heading": "Subject, Predicate and their types",
  "topics": [
    {
      "heading": "Subject, Predicate and their types ",
      "questions": [
        {
            "questionNo": 1,
            "question": "Subjects can only include a ‘Noun or a Noun Equivalent’.",
            "options": [
                "Correct",
                "Incorrect"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 2,
            "question": "Predicates can be phrases.",
            "options": [
                "Correct",
                "Incorrect"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 3,
            "question": "I and Ryan prefer hot chocolate. In the above sentence the subject is:",
            "options": [
                "Simple",
                "Complete",
                "Compound",
                "Both b and c"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 4,
            "question": "Regular adjectives are a part of:",
            "options": [
                "Pre-modifiers",
                "Complete Predicates",
                "Objects",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 5,
            "question": "Subordinating conjunctions can help in the formation of Compound subjects and Predicates.",
            "options": [
                "Correct",
                "Incorrect"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 6,
            "question": "A post-modifier includes:",
            "options": [
                "Pronouns",
                "Nouns",
                "Articles",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 7,
            "question": "The sun rises in the east. <br>‘The sun’ is the:",
            "options": [
                "Compound subject",
                "Simple subject",
                "Complete subject",
                "Both A and B"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 8,
            "question": "I have been waiting since yesterday. <br>The verb phrase in the sentence is:",
            "options": [
                "Have been",
                "Waiting since",
                "Have been waiting",
                "Both A and B"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 9,
            "question": "It is difficult to adjust with nasty people.<br> The complete predicate of the above sentence includes",
            "options": [
                "Is difficult to adjust",
                "With nasty people",
                "Is difficult to adjust with nasty people",
                "To adjust"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 10,
            "question": "Determiners include:",
            "options": [
                "6 components",
                "5 components",
                "7 components",
                "4 components"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 11,
            "question": "Some fresh fruits, sourdough bread, raspberry jam and a simple tofu salad was my breakfast today. <br>The compound subject in the sentence is:",
            "options": [
                "Some fresh fruits, sourdough bread, raspberry jam and a simple tofu salad",
                "fruits, sourdough bread, raspberry jam and a simple tofu salad",
                "fruits, sourdough bread, raspberry jam and a tofu salad",
                "fruits, sourdough bread, raspberry jam and tofu salad",
                "fruits, sourdough bread, raspberry jam and a simple tofu salad"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 12,
            "question": "Simple predicates include:",
            "options": [
                "Modifiers",
                "Objects",
                "Complements",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 13,
            "question": "She came home. <br>The above sentence has a verb phrase.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 14,
            "question": "Identify the modifiers in the sentence below: <br>The matter is completely off-hand now.",
            "options": [
                "The, completely off-hand",
                "The, now",
                "The, completely",
                "The, is completely"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 15,
            "question": "Move. <br>The subject in this sentence is:",
            "options": [
                "You",
                "Not mentioned but understood",
                "Passive",
                "Both A and B"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 16,
            "question": "An infinitive phrase can be a part of:",
            "options": [
                "Pre-modifier",
                "Post-modifier",
                "Both A and B",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 17,
            "question": "How are you? <br>What is the subject in the sentence",
            "options": [
                "Simple subject",
                "Not clear",
                "You",
                "The sentence does not have any subject."
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 18,
            "question": "The girl in the cyan dress is my sister. <br>Identify the post-modifier.",
            "options": [
                "Cyan dress",
                "In the cyan dress",
                "Is my sister",
                "Both B and C"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 19,
            "question": "Not only my siblings but I am also in support of the victim’s family.<br> What is correct about the above sentence?",
            "options": [
                "The sentence has a compound subject.",
                "Both A and B"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 20,
            "question": "In a sentence, a ‘pronoun’ can also be the subject.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 21,
            "question": "He constructed the Na’eem house and founded the charity hospital.<br> The complete predicate of the sentence contains:",
            "options": [
                "Two finite verbs",
                "Two objects",
                "Two modifiers",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 22,
            "question": "There are only three ways of forming a complete subject.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 23,
            "question": "Who is this?<br> Identify the subject.",
            "options": [
                "Who",
                "This",
                "Both a and b",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 24,
            "question": "Can a compound subject be a combination of two or more(generally two) simple subjects or complete subjects?",
            "options": [
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 25,
            "question": "Numbers are a part of:",
            "options": [
                "Determiners",
                "Pre-modifiers",
                "Both A and B",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        }
    ]
    
    
    
    }
  ]
}
